Guide to the Student Organizations Reference Collection, 1913-ongoing UA.01.11.0014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Student Organizations reference collection
1913-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0014
3 Linear Feet
2000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Student Organizations Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
The Student Organizations Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. It contains subject files, flyers, clippings, along with some organizational records of undergraduate, graduate, and professional student organizations. It does not include fraternities, sororities, affiliated religious organizations, student housing groups, or groups only associated with Trinity College (-to 1924). Materials in this collection date from 1913 onward.
Related Material
Fraternities and Sororities collection, 1931-2001.
University Archives, Duke University.
Living Groups Reference Collection, 1964-2001.
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.; Duke University -- Students -- Social conditions; Duke University -- Students -- Political activity
- Student government - general (Box 1)
- Student organizations-general (Box 1)
- Student organizations-Duke University, 1969-70 (Box 1)
- Student organizations and enterprises, 1838-1938 (outline) / Ben M. Patrick, 1938 (Box 1)
- Minority student organizations & multicultural groups (Box 1)
- Activists for Israel (Box 1)
- Adopt-a-Grandparent (Box 1)
- A.E.F. Club, undated (Box 1)
- Alpha Kappa Kappa (Medical Fraternity) (Box 1)
- Alpha Omega Alpha (Medical Honor Society) (Box 1)
- Alpha Sigma Sigma (Box 1)
- Amalgamated Frosh (Box 1)
- Amateur Radio Association (Box 1)
- American Bar Association (Box 1)
- American Society of Mechanical Engineers--Duke Chapter (Box 1)
- American Student Federation (Box 1)
- American Student Union (Box 1)
- Americans for Democratic Action (Box 1)
- Amnesty International (Box 1)
- Another Drama Group (Box 1)
- Anti-Nuclear Groups (Box 1)
- Arab-American Student Association (Box 1)
- Archery Club (Box 1)
- Asian Business Club (Box 1)
- Associated Students of Duke University (ASDU); see also ASDU records (Box 1)
- Associated Students of Duke University (ASDU) – History (Box 1)
- Associated Students of Duke University (ASDU) – Free University (Box 1)
- Associated Students of Duke University (ASDU) – Student Perspective (Box 1)
- Association for Computing Machinery (Box 1)
- Association of Duke Women (Box 1)
- Athena Literary Society (Box 1)
- Autocracy Smashers (Box 1)
- AWARE: The Black and Latino Political Awareness Coalition (Box 1)
- Ballroom Dance Club (Box 2)
- Bench and Bar, 1979-1981 (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Beta Omega Sigma (Local Honorary Sophomore Fraternity) (Box 2)
- Black and Latino MBA Organization (Box 2)
- Blue Boors (Box 2)
- Blue Imp (Box 2)
- Blue Jeans (Box 2)
- Blue Stocking Club (Box 2)
- Breaking Down the Walls (Box 2)
- Bridge Club (Box 2)
- Brooks Literary Society: see Athena Literary Society (Box 2)
- Building Awareness through Shared Experiences (BASES) (Box 2)
- Campus Coordinating Council (Box 2)
- Campus Outreach Opportunity League (COOL) (Box 2)
- Cat's Head Club (Box 2)
- Central American Solidarity Committee (Box 2)
- Chaplains of Future Wars (Box 2)
- Chess Club (Box 2)
- Chinese Student Association (Box 2)
- Circle K / Kiwanis (Box 2)
- Civitan Club (Box 2)
- Club Sports (Box 2)
- Coalition for a Women's Center at Duke (Box 2)
- Coffeehouses (Box 2)
- Coffeehouses – Celestial Omnibus, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
- Coffeehouses – The Duke Coffeehouse, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
- College Bowl, 1983 (Box 2)
- Commando Club (Box 2)
- Committee against Racism (Box 2)
- Committee for Student Concerns (Box 2)
- Committee to Reverse the Arms Race (Box 2)
- Common Cause (Box 2)
- Community Service Council (Box 2)
- Concilio Latino/Hispano/Americano (Box 2)
- Dance Black (Box 2)
- Dance Group (Box 2)
- Dancing Devils (Box 2)
- Delta Group (Box 2)
- Delta Upsilon Kappa (Chemistry Honor Fraternity) (Box 2)
- Divina Commedia, 1968 (Box 2)
- Divinity Dames (Box 3)
- DRAGO: Duke Recreational Adventure Gaming Organization (Box 3)
- DukAnime, 1998 (Box 3)
- Duke Acquaintance Rape Education (DARE), 1996 (Box 3)
- DukeAFRICA, 2015- (Box 3)
- Duke Ambassadors (Box 3)
- Duke Asian American Theater, 2016- (Box 3)
- Duke Business Club, 2000- (Box 3)
- Duke Chapter of the Council on International Relations and United Nations Affairs (Box 3)
- Duke Chinese Dance, 2014- (Box 3)
- Duke Coalition for Peace in the Middle East (Box 3)
- Duke Conservative Union (Box 3)
- Duke Dance Club (Box 3)
- Duke Debate Club/Society, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
- Duke Democrats, ca. 1976-1996 (Box 3)
- Duke Draft Coalition (Box 3)
- Duke Drive for Muscular Dystrophy, 1976 (Box 3)
- Duke Flying Club (Box 3)
- Duke Forum on Critical Issues, 1980 (Box 3)
- Duke Free Man (Box 3)
- Duke Gay, Bisexual and Lesbian Association, 1976-2000; see also DGBLA records (Box 3)
- Duke Graduate and Professional Lesbian, Gay & Bisexual Association (Box 3)
- Duke Independent Film Festival, 2016- (Box 3)
- Duke Japan-America Club (Box 3)
- Duke Makers, 2015- (Box 3)
- Duke Musical Clubs (Box 3)
- Duke New Music Ensemble, 2014- (Box 3)
- DukeOpen, 2013 (Box 3)
- Duke Out (Box 3)
- Duke Real Estate Club, 2015- (Box 3)
- Duke Robotics Club (Box 3)
- Duke Sailing Club, 1964 (Box 3)
- Duke Scuba Club (Box 3)
- Duke Student Movement (Box 3)
- DSM, email correspondence (Box 3)
- Duke Students for a Free Tibet (Box 3)
- Duke Students for Awareness of Energy & Environment (Box 3)
- Duke Students for Energy Conservation (Box 3)
- Duke Students for Life (Box 4)
- Duke Students for Safer Alternatives to Nuclear Power (Box 4)
- Duke Union for Media and the Arts, 2014- (Box 4)
- Duke University Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1963-1964 (Box 4)
- Duke University Dating Service (DUDS) (Box 4)
- Duke University Marching Band; see also Duke University Marching Band records. (Box 4)
- Duke University Music Exchange (D.U.M.E.) (Box 4)
- Duke University Network of Entrepreneurs (DUNE) (Box 4)
- Duke University Photographic Society, 1978 (Box 4)
- Duke University Rescue Squad (Box 4)
- Duke University Steering Board, 1948-1951 (Box 4)
- Duke University Wargames Team, 1967 (Box 4)
- Duke Women's Coalition (Box 4)
- Duke Women's Crew Club, 1975-1981 (Box 4)
- Duke Young Republican Club, 1969 (Box 4)
- Duke Youth Caucus (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Dukes and Duchesses (Box 4)
- Duke and Duchesses Handbook, 2008 (Box 4)
- Educated Womanpower Committee (Box 4)
- Environmental Alliance, 2014- (Box 4)
- Film Society (Box 4)
- Forestry Club (Box 5)
- Forum for the Advancement of Students in Science and Technology, Duke Chapter, 1977 (Box 5)
- Freshman Advisory Council (Box 5)
- Frisbee Club (Box 5)
- Fuqua2Duke Mentor Program (Box 5)
- The Future is Now, 2016- (Box 5)
- Gamer's Club (Box 5)
- Gente Apriendiendo Para Nuevas Oportunidades (GANO), 2016- (Box 5)
- German Club (Box 5)
- Global Nomads, 1993 (Box 5)
- Golden Key National Honor Society (Box 5)
- Graduate and Professional Student Council, 1982- (Box 5)
- Graduate and Professional Women's Network (Box 5)
- Graduate Education Association (Box 5)
- Graduate Employee/Student Organization (Box 5)
- Graduate English Association (Box 5)
- Graduate Student Association, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
- Graduate Wives Club of Duke University, 1964 (Box 5)
- Hats Off!, 1986 (Box 5)
- HeforShe@Duke, 2016- (Box 5)
- Hideaway Bar, 1981-2001 (Box 5)
- Hindu Students Council (Box 5)
- History Majors Union (Box 5)
- Honor Council (Box 5)
- Hoof'n'Horn; see also Hoof'n'Horn records (Box 5)
- Hunger Task Force (Box 5)
- Ice Hockey Club (Box 5)
- Independent Students Association, 1995 (Box 5)
- Inside Joke, 2015- (Box 5)
- Intercomm (Students Aware of the Need for International Communication), 1983 (Box 5)
- Intercommunity Council (Box 5)
- Inter-Galactic Food Conspiracy/Duke Food Co-op, 1976-1980 (Box 5)
- Inter-Governmental Council (Box 5)
- International Association, 1980-1984 (Box 5)
- International Business Club: The World at Fuqua (Box 5)
- International Council (Box 5)
- International Relations Club (Box 5)
- Investment Club (Box 5)
- Italian Club (Box 5)
- Kappa Delta Pi (Local Professional Society) (Box 5)
- Karamu (Box 5)
- Karate Club (Box 5)
- Latter-Day Saints Institute, 1973 (Box 5)
- Men Acting for Change (Box 5)
- Men's Pan-Hellenic Council (Box 5)
- Men's Student Government Association; see also MSGA records (Box 5)
- Men's Student Government Association. Student Perspective, 1964 (Box 6)
- Middle South Model United Nations, 1966 (Box 6)
- Mi Gente (Box 6)
- Modern Black Mass Choir (Box 6)
- Momentum, 2014- (Box 6)
- NAACP-Duke Chapter (Box 6)
- National Alliance Against Racist & Political Repression--Duke Chapter (Box 6)
- National Organization for Women (NOW) (Box 6)
- Native American Student Coalition (Box 6)
- Nereidians (Box 6)
- North Carolina Public Interest Research Group NC-PIRG (Box 6)
- North Carolina Student Rural Health Coalition, 1980-2000 (Box 6)
- Old Trinity Club (Box 6)
- Orchid Society (Box 6)
- Orienteering Club (Box 6)
- Out of the Blue (Box 6)
- Outing Club (Box 6)
- People's Productions (Box 6)
- Peter Grimes Society (Box 6)
- Phi Delta Phi (National Legal Fraternity) (Box 6)
- Philosophy Discussion Group (Box 6)
- Photo Club (Box 6)
- Pi Gamma Mu (Social Science Honor Society) (Box 6)
- Pi Tau Sigma (Mechanical Engineering Honor Society) (Box 6)
- Pisces (Peer Information Service for Counseling and Education in Sexuality) (Box 6)
- Pitchforks (Box 6)
- Pre-Medical Society (Box 6)
- Pro-Palestinian Group (Box 6)
- Project Build (Box 6)
- Project Pride (Box 6)
- Project Wild (Wilderness Initiatives for Learning at Duke) (Box 6)
- Radical Academic Union, 1975-1977 (Box 6)
- Rugby Team (Men's) (Box 6)
- Sabrosura, 2014- (Box 6)
- Sailing Club (Box 6)
- Sandals (Box 6)
- Save the Dogs Committee (Box 6)
- Save the Efe Pygmy (STEP) (Box 6)
- Screen/Society (Box 6)
- Secret Societies (Box 6)
- Self-Knowledge Symposium (Box 6)
- Shoe 'N' Slipper Club (Box 6)
- Sigma Tau Delta (National Professional English Fraternity) (Box 6)
- Sigma Theta Tau (National Honor Society for Nurses) (Box 6)
- Sky Devils (Box 6)
- Society for Creative Anachronisms (Box 6)
- Society of Duke Fellows (Box 6)
- Society of Physics Students (Box 6)
- Southern Student Organizing Committee (Box 7)
- Speak of the Devil (Box 7)
- The Standard (online publication), 2015- (Box 7)
- Student-Employee Relations Coalition (Box 7)
- Student Project for University Development, 1976 and undated (Box 7)
- Student Radio Stations: WDBS, WDUK, WDUR, WXDU; see also records (Box 7)
- Students Acting for Residential Change (Box 7)
- Students Against Nuclear Energy (SANE) (Box 7)
- Students Against Sweatshops / Sullivan principles (Box 7)
- Students for a Democratic Central America (Box 7)
- Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) (Box 7)
- Students for Academic Reform (Box 7)
- Students for Israel (Box 7)
- Students for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (Box 7)
- Students for the Exploration and Development of Space (Box 7)
- Students International Meditation Society (Box 7)
- Students to Advance Bio-Ethics (STAB) (Box 7)
- Students Towards Equality and Prevention of Sexism (STEPS) (Box 7)
- Students with an Alternative Vision for East (Box 7)
- Tau Kappa Alpha (Forensic Honor Fraternity) (Box 7)
- Taurian Players (Box 7)
- Terpsichorean (Box 7)
- Texas Brotherhood of Duke Students, 1968 (Box 7)
- Tocqueville Society (Box 7)
- Turkish Student Association (Box 7)
- T.V. Club (Box 7)
- Ultimate (Box 7)
- Undergraduate Judicial Board, 1981- (Box 7)
- Undergraduates Committed to Excellence in Education (Box 7)
- United Duke Students (Box 7)
- United Nations Model General Assembly (Box 7)
- United Student Front (Box 7)
- We Are Here Duke, 2015- (Box 7)
- We Magazine, 2015- (Box 7)
- West Campus Escort Service (Box 7)
- Who Needs Feminism?, 2013 (Box 7)
- Women in Science and Engineering (WISE) (Box 7)
- Women's Alliance (Box 7)
- Young Americans for Freedom (Box 7)
- Young Conservatives (Box 7)
- Young Democrats (Box 7)
- Young Libertarians (Box 7)
- Young Men's Christian Association; see also YMCA records (Box 7)
- Young Women's Christian Association; see also YWCA records (Box 7)
- Youth Outreach (Box 7)
- Zionist Action Coalition (Box 7)